你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if you're number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第22集
Person of Interest S01E22 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
还以为你已经把这玩意儿关掉了
Thought you would have turned this thing off by now.
我们明天才把它移交出去
We turn it over tomorrow.
我要让它尽可能长时间地在线
I'm keeping it online as long as possible.
过去的50亿年里没有你的机器
The world has been spinning for 5 billion years
地球一样转  哈罗德
without your machine, Harold.
我看再多一个晚上也没事
I'm sure it will be fine for one more night.
说实话  我很高兴能摆脱这玩意儿
Honestly, I'll be glad to be rid of the thing.
这个"玩意儿"已经成功挽救无数生命
This "thing" has already saved countless lives.
你是指无数"紧要的"生命
You mean countless relevant lives.
我们必须区分轻重缓急
We had to draw the line somewhere.
每个人都是某些人心中最紧要的
Everyone is relevant to someone.
如果你的生命中
You would know that if you had
有你真心在乎的人  你就会明白的
anyone in your life you cared about.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你的成就无以伦比
What you've built here is incredible.
其他人将没有机会告诉你这点
And no one else will ever get a chance to tell you that.
我明白你做出的决定何等艰难
And I don't envy the decisions you've had to make,
但我真的担心你
but I worry about you.
七年来  你一直观察着别人的生活
Seven years, you've been watching other people's lives,
他们的计划  他们的人际交往
their plans, their relationships.
现在应该抽出点时间给自己了
Maybe it's time for you to invest a little time on your own.
谁说我没时间给自己
Who says I haven't?
我知道你喜欢保密  哈罗德
I know you like your secrets, Harold,
但如果你已找到真爱
but if you had found someone,
我肯定早听到耳朵长茧子了
I would never hear the end of it.
你好啊  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
准备好抓些腐败警察了吗
You ready to bust some dirty cops?
西蒙斯想让我下周去见HR的头
Simmons wants me to meet the HR brass next week.
那就下周再给我电话  我正忙着调查呢
Then call me next week. I'm busy with research.
调查
Research?
你是又去跟踪你老板了吧
You mean following your boss again.
你都跟了他好几周了
You tailed him for weeks.
连他住哪里都没找到
You couldn't even find out where he lives.
是啊  除非你弄到地址
Yeah, well, unless you got an address,
否则咱俩不过半斤八两罢了
I'd say that we're both striking out, huh?
-芬奇  -我们得见一面  里瑟先生
- Finch? - We need to meet, Mr. Reese.
刚刚收到了新号码
We've just received another number.
音频拦截
主体：吉布斯  西欧多尔  J
我们的谈话绝不能外泄
We never had this conversation,
电话追踪
我想亲自感谢你
but I wanted to thank you personally
主体：佩克  亨利  L
所做的迪拜报告
for your work on the Dubai report.
如果不是你发现了卡尔森
If you hadn't flagged Carlson--
什么卡尔森  长官
Carlson, sir?
音线压力
严重
他是整件事情的关键
He was the key to the whole thing.
-你挽救了情报系统  孩子  -谢谢长官
- You saved our asses, son. - Thank you, sir.
亨利・佩克  33岁
Henry Peck, 33 years old,
未婚  独居在玳瑁湾
never married, lives alone in Turtle Bay.
佩克是名注册金融分析师
Peck works as a chartered financial analyst,
通俗点说  他负责为一家小型金融企业
which is a fancy way of saying he picks stocks
"德克和诺斯联合公司"挑选股票
for a small financial firm, Decker and North Associates.
你有没有在听
Are you following me?
金融分析师  引人入胜啊
Financial analyst. It's riveting.
总不能都是婴儿或者黑帮教父吧
Well, they can't all be baby's and mafia dons.
到目前为止  亨利・佩克最突出一点就是
So far, the most unusual thing about Henry Peck is that
他的安保措施异常完备
he has better-than-average security habits.
我还无法黑入他的留言箱
I haven't been able to hack his voicemail,
电子邮箱或者在线账户
his email, or any online accounts.
神秘  独居
Secretive, solitary...
他跟你挺像  芬奇
He's just like you, Finch.
你是怎么拿到他的号码的
So how'd you get his number?
约翰  咱们有机器
Well, John, there's this machine...
没错  但你不是在这里拿到号码的
Yeah, but you didn't get it here.
不是
No...
情况要更微妙
It's much more subtle than that.
我也该知道
And it's time I knew
机器是如何与你进行沟通的
how the machine communicates with you.
为什么
Why?
恕我直言
Not to be blunt,
不过如果你一旦发生意外
But wouldn't you want me to keep doing this
难道你不想我一个人继续下去吗
if something ever happened to you?
如果发生意外  我有
If something ever happens, I have...
应急预案
a contingency.
迟早有一天
Well, sooner or later,
你的秘密会被发现的  芬奇
you're gonna need to let the cat out of the bag, Finch.
直译：你要让猫从包里出来的
好奇会害死猫的  里瑟先生
Curiosity kills cats, Mr. Reese.
芬奇  到目前为止对佩克来说最大的危险
Finch, so far the biggest threat to Peck
是被纸划伤
is a paper cut.
他个人资料方面有什么幸运发现吗
Any luck getting more info on him?
光凭幸运是搞不定的
It's gonna take more than luck.
公司的防火墙比佩克的还要安全
The firm's firewall is even better than Peck's.
是啊  我能看清他的办公室了
Yeah, I've got line of sight on his office,
但就是接收不到他的无线或手机信号
but I can't get any signals from his Wi-Fi or cell.
他在IQZ电信大楼上班
He works in the IQZ telecom building.
金融企业就喜欢呆在有互联网集成器的地方
Financial firms like to co-locate with internet hubs,
以方便他们的交易比别人快个几微微秒
so they can get their trades in a few picoseconds faster.
如果接受不到信号
If you're not getting a signal,
可能是被IQZ屏蔽了
it's probably just interference from IQZ's antennas.
没法连上他的手机  芬奇
Couldn't bluejack him, Finch,
所以我改用传统办法  无线窃听器
so I went old school... wireless bug.
艾丽西娅  我是亨利・佩克  又打来了
Alicia, it's Henry Peck... again.
我真的需要跟你谈谈
Listen, I really need to talk to you,
请给我回个电话
so please just give me a call
咱们找地方见一面  好吗
and we'll find a place to meet, okay?
艾丽西娅  谁啊  前女友吗
Alicia...so who's Alicia? An ex-girlfriend?
还是想甩掉的女友
Or someone he wishes was a girlfriend?
佩克先生  你忘了清除电话记录了
Mr. Peck! You forgot to wipe your phone.
他还得清除电话记录吗
He has to wipe his phone's memory?
现在高管海外旅行经常会有此类要求
It's become common practice for executes traveling overseas,
但在这里  我还是第一次听说
but that's the first time I've heard of it here.
抱歉  我今天有点走神了
Sorry, I guess I'm just a little distracted today.
你工作太累了
Well, you work too hard.
我要知道佩克在办公室干些什么
I want to know what goes on in Peck's office,
既然我们在室外弄不到信号
And since we can't get signals out,
我只能施展魅力混进去了
I'll have to charm my way in.
您有什么事吗
May I help you?
是的
Yes...
约翰・鲁尼  财产经理人
John Rooney, assets.
我来见个人
I have a meeting with...
汤姆・布鲁斯特  注册金融分析师
Thomas Brewster, C.F.A.
汤姆・布鲁斯特
Tom Brewster.
我先前跟他通过电话
I'm a tad early.
窃听器信号消失了
We just lost the feed from our bug.
我这没有此次会面的记录
I don't have a record of that meeting,
没有预约恐怕您不能进去
And I'm afraid nobody's allowed back without an appointment.
也许您应该重新安排一次
Perhaps you should reschedule.
也许是啊
Perhaps I should.
鄙人莫名惊诧啊  里瑟先生
I'm surprised, Mr. Reese.
那位好姑娘居然对你的魅力无动于衷
That nice young lady seemed somehow impervious to your charms.
那位好姑娘在桌子底下拿点45的手枪指着我
That nice young lady had a .45 pointed at me under her desk.
大门用的是自旋锁  还站着一个警卫
There's a guard and a spin lock on the main door.
这不是家金融公司  是间SCIF
This isn't a financial firm. It's a S.C.I.F.
敏感信息隔离机构
Sensitive Compartmented Information Facility.
政府的秘密组织
Secret government installation
用来保护机密数据的
designed to protect classified data.
佩克也不是什么金融分析师
Peck's no financial analyst either.
他是个非官方卧底  算是间谍
He's a N.O.C., some kind of spy.
你还觉得他生活无趣
And you thought he didn't have a life.
我们要怎么对间谍采取间谍行为呢
So how do we spy on a spy?
我想我有办法进入了  里瑟先生
I believe I've found a way in, Mr. Reese.
佩克办公室的安全设备对无线信号能拦截
The security in Peck's office blocks wireless signals,
但是对传统线路呢
but what about good old-fashioned wires?
每间办公室都要靠咖啡因运作
And since every office runs on caffeine,
我们只要把摄像头和接收器
All we have to do is hide a camera and transceiver
藏在一台崭新的咖啡机里
inside a shiny new coffeemaker,
装上线路让信号通过电力系统传出来
wire it to send data out through the electrical system,
然后等他们把咖啡机电源插上
then wait for them to plug it in.
我再给你解释一遍吧
Let me play that for you again.
有信号了  芬奇
Got a signal, finch.
这是哈桑・本・埃米尔的声音
That's the voice of Hassan Ben Amir.
我在米德堡的时候天天都能听到
I listened to him every day when I was at Fort Meade.
位于马里兰州  美国国安局所在地
哈桑是个大人物
Hassan is a major player,
一直在资助中东的恐怖活动
funding terror throughout the Middle East,
他打电话到纽约  我们就必须加以注意
and if he's calling New York, we need to pay attention.
现在  根据我们截获的
Now, if you'll look at these intercepts...
佩克是个情报分析员
Peck's an intelligence analyst,
而且听起来  还挺出色
and from the sound of it, a damn good one.
所以他们身处通信大厦
That's why they're in a telecom building.
这样能进入传输线路
They can jack into the feeds.
这是个国安局监听站
It's an NSA listening station.
那我们就好好听着吧
I guess we'd better listen.
好了  芬奇  佩克刚到家
All right, Finch, Peck just got home.
来看看这位间谍晚上都干些什么吧
Time to see what our spy does at night.
到目前为止  啥事没有
So far...not much.
并不是每个人是交际花  里瑟先生
Not everyone is a social butterfly, Mr. Reese.
对某些人来说  人际互动非常困难
For some of us, human interaction is difficult.
别用"人际互动"这种词  或许有助改善
Not calling it "human interaction" might help.
没日没夜地工作
Works around the clock,
没有朋友  没有家人
No sign of friends or family...
可怜的家伙生活太无聊了
Poor guy doesn't seem to have much of a life.
我们可没资格说人家
Well, we can hardly fault him for that,
别人还都当我们已死呢
seeing as everyone thinks we're dead.
佩克先生  你在吗
Mr. Peck, are you there?
佩克先生
Mr. Peck?
陈先生
Mr. Chen?
你的房东打电话来投诉
Your landlord called with a complaint.
介意我们检查一下吗  佩克先生
You mind if we have a look around, Mr. Peck?
这是怎么回事
What's this about?
我也想知道呢
I was wondering the same thing.
显然你的烟雾探测器今天坏了
Apparently your smoke detector was malfunctioning today.
陈先生进来修理的时候
When Mr. Chen entered the apartment to fix it...
发现了这个
He saw these.
安非他明  份量够判重罪了
Adderall, felony weight.
上瘾性兴奋剂
什么  这不是我的
What? No, that's not mine.
到警局后我们肯定会给你机会
We're sure they'll give you a chance to explain it
好好解释的  走吧
down at the station. Let's go.
等等  我想在这里就解释清楚
Hold on. I'd rather have the chance to explain it right here.
芬奇  我想佩克的生活
Finch, I think Peck's life
开始有点意思了
just got a little more interesting.
-芬奇  -窃听器回声
- Finch? - Feedback from the bug.
肯定是有杂音混入频道了
Something else must be on the channel.
清除一下就
Trying to clean it...
是相同的信号
It's the same signal.
他身上还有别的窃听器  有别人在监听
There's another bug. Someone else is listening.
是啊  我好像看到他了
Yeah, and I think I've got eyes on him.
我想那些毒品是栽赃的  芬奇
I think those drugs were planted, Finch.
佩克被陷害了
I think Peck's being set up.
问题是  为什么
Question is, why?
《本区》
你会买二十本同样的杂志吗  卡特
You ever buy 20 copies of the same magazine, Carter?
-什么  -没什么
- What? - Never mind.
有什么情况
Do you have news?
佩克一小时前保释离开了
Peck made bail about an hour ago.
我尽可能拿到了亨利・佩克的全部资料
I got everything I could on Henry Peck
并不多
which isn't much.
煎绿茶
只有一个指控记录  佩克申诉撤销了
Only one charge on his record, and Peck had that expunged.
是吸毒记录吗
Does he have a history of drug abuse?
跟吸毒无关  是张超速罚单
Not even close. It was a speeding ticket.
克雷默纸业公司
编号JGS-0031
他居然为了超速指控去申诉
He fought to get a speeding ticket off his record?
这是"原则问题"
It was "the principle of the thing."
至少佩克在寄给法官的  用词严谨的
At least, that's what Peck said in his meticulous,
长达78页的报告里是这么说的
78-page brief he sent the judge.
真是爱死这种一根筋到底的人了
Got to love a man who doesn't know when to quit.
-谢了  卡特  -不谢
- Thanks, Carter. - Yep.
佩克不是瘾君子  有人把毒品栽赃给他
Well, Peck's no addict. Somebody planted those drugs.
我去了帕克办公室
I visited the bodega
街边的那家酒窖
that's down the street from Peck's office...
进入他们公司的无线网络
and chatted up their wireless network,
下载了这段录像
downloading this video
有人闯进了他的公寓
of someone breaking into his apartment.
这就是我昨天晚上看到的人
I'm pretty sure that's the same guy I saw last night.
此人受过精心训练
Whoever he is, he's well-trained.
有人盯上了佩克  我们得找出原因
Someone's targeting Peck. We need to figure out why.
在找出幕后主使之前
And until we figure out who's after him...
我会看好佩克的
I'll keep an eye on Peck.
亨利  我们得谈谈
Henry, we need to talk.
我们知道了你被捕的事  还有吸毒的事
We know about the arrest and drug problem.
我根本不吸毒
There is no drug problem.
根据第13526条管理条例
Under executive order 13526,
你的安全许可已失效
your security clearance is suspended.
需等候调查
Pending investigation.
现责令你开始行政休假
You're hereby placed on administrative leave,
非商业机构雇员因遭控行为不检暂离工作岗位
但薪水和福利不变
立即生效
Effective immediately.
拜托  长官  你不能...
Please, sir, you can't just--
出去  亨利
I need you out, Henry.
从现在起  你不能在国安局工作了
As of this moment, you can't work for the NSA.
在这儿工作的七年里
In the seven years I've worked here,
我吃过最强效的药是阿司匹林
the strongest drug I've taken is aspirin.
这事内情不单纯
There's something else going on here.
我是被陷害的
I'm being set up.
如果你是说这里面有什么更大的阴谋
If you're alleging some greater conspiracy here,
我会把这些加进你档案里
I can add that to your file,
但这会显得你情绪异常
but it might make you seem unstable.
质疑权威  然后被视为疯子
Question authority and they call you crazy.
佩克被逼走了
Peck's being forced out.
我不知道你怎么想  里瑟先生
I don't know about you, Mr. Reese,
但我很想知道原因何在
But I'd very much like to know why.
很抱歉一再打电话
I'm sorry to keep calling,
但兹事体大
but it's really important.
拜托  我只是想和泰德・吉布斯谈谈  我
Please, I just need to speak to Ted Gibbons, my--
你好
Hello?
查到那个名字没  芬奇
Recognize that name, Finch?
西欧多尔・吉布斯  国安局副局长
Theodore Gibbons, deputy director of the NSA.
他越级了  还不止一级
He's going over his boss' head, way over.
佩克惹的  是大麻烦
Whatever Peck's into, it's big.
"出国了"  真的吗
"Out of the country"? Really?
但总部里有人刚告诉我
Because some guy at headquarters just told me
他在开会  拜托
he was in a meeting. Please.
我只不过是问了问题
Now, all I did was ask questions.
任何合格的分析员都会  喂
Any decent analyst wou-- Hello?
喂
Hello?
有人因为佩克问了问题而毁了他的生活
Someone is destroying Peck's life for asking questions.
他问了什么
About what?
芬奇  佩克家楼下的监控摄像头
Finch, the security camera over Peck's door,
昨晚是不是好的
was it working last night?
是啊  怎么了
Yes. Why?
有人闯进他家了
Because someone's in his apartment.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
里瑟先生  一切都好
Mr. Reese, is everything o--
看来不太好
I'll take that as a no.
芬奇  这是政府训练出来的刺客
Finch, I know a government trained assassin when I see one.
他们不光要除掉佩克的工作
They're not just after Peck's job.
华盛顿有人想致他于死地
Someone in Washington wants him dead.
那我们得保护他  里瑟先生
Then we need to protect him, Mr. Reese.
他跑不了太远
He can't have gotten far.
我用窃听器追踪他
I'll use the bug to track him down.
检测到窃听器
-你好  -你好  我找泰德・吉布斯
- Hello? - Hi, Ted Gibbons please.
你好
Hello?
吉布斯副局长  我叫亨利・佩克
Deputy director Gibbons, my name is Henry Peck.
我在你手下工作
I work for you.
这是我女儿的手机
This is my daughter's cell phone.
你怎么弄到这号码的
How did you get this number?
很抱歉打扰你  长官
I'm sorry to bother you, sir,
但有人想杀我
But someone just tried to kill me.
什么
What?
三周前  你秘密打电话给我
Now, three weeks ago, you called me off the record
祝贺我提交的一份报告
to congratulate me on a report that I submitted
协助了一次高级别捕获行动
that led to the high-level arrest
目标叫卡尔森
of a man named Carlson,
但我从没听说过什么卡尔森
but I never heard of a Carlson.
他的名字在你的报告里
His name was in your report.
但不是我写上去的
But I didn't put it there.
有人把这名字塞进了我的报告里
Someone slipped this name into my report,
而那个名字正是
and that one name was the key
阻止一起大规模恐怖袭击的关键
to stopping a major terrorist attack.
我只不过是问了问题
All I did was ask questions.
结果却被人逮捕  丢了工作
I have been arrested, I have lost my job,
他们还试图处死我
and they're trying to execute me,
我只想知道原因
and I just want to know why.
不许再打给我
Don't ever call me again.
你还好吗  芬奇
Everything okay, Finch?
我知道谁想让佩克死  也知道为什么
I know who wants Peck dead and I know why.
我知道他问了什么问题
I know what he's been asking questions about.
他们想让他死全因为我
They want him dead because of me.
亨利・佩克全不知情
Henry Peck doesn't know it,
但他一直在问关于机器的事
but he's been asking about the machine.
不用了
No.
出什么事了  艾丽西娅
Is something wrong, Alicia?
你指除了密谋监视无数美国民众
You mean other than being a part of an ongoing conspiracy
之外的事情吗
to spy on millions of Americans?
是的  但那都是出于好意
Yes, but it's all for a good cause.
后天  货运车将会驶离得梅因
Day after tomorrow, freight train out of Des Moines.
最后六车  货单会显示运输货品是
The last six cars, the manifest will list the contents
已淘汰的电脑部件
as decommissioned computer parts.
你那边怎么样了
What about things on your end?
整个设施是按照你的要求建造的
The facility is designed to the specifications you gave us,
选址方面我们非常谨慎
and it's discreet, where we're putting it.
没人会去找
No one's going to go looking.
还有什么问题吗
Any other problem?
消息封锁
Dissemination.
我们有协议的
We have a protocol in place.
机器一给出嫌疑人
If the machine identifies a suspect,
就会把名字交给合适的部门去解决
the name will find its way to the right people...
且消息源无法被追溯
with no way to trace the intel back to the source.
绝对无法被追溯  否则
There can't be. Otherwise...
我们就全被钉死在那个
We'll all wind up someplace
没人会去找的地方了
where no one's going to go looking.
世上只有八个人知道它的存在
Eight people in the world know it exists.
必须保持住这个数字
We need to keep it that way.
七个  奈森
Seven, Nathan.
只有七个  除非你又和谁说了
Seven people, unless you told someone.
拜托  艾丽西娅  你知道我数学多差
Come on, Alicia, you know I'm terrible at math.
你那边的人
The people on your end...
他们可靠吗
You sure about them?
确保没人发现那台机器
Making sure no one ever finds out
是我们的工作
about the machine is our problem.
我们会搞定
We'll take care of it.
我们已经认识很久了  艾丽西娅
We've known each other a long time, Alicia.
你在为某件事不安
Something's got you rattled.
我没事  奈森
I'm fine, Nathan.
这件事搞定后我就安心了
I'll be happier when this thing is settled
我就能回去正常工作了
and I can go back to my day job.
那到底是什么工作
And what's that exactly?
保密
Classified.
现在你可以请我喝酒了
You can buy me that drink now.
怎么了  卡特
Yeah, Carter?
佩克的邻居报了警
One of Peck's neighbors called 911,
说他们看见两个男人在那公寓里打架
said they saw two men fighting in his apartment.
没什么事吧
Is everything okay?
问题已经解决了
The situation has been resolved.
我们现在很好  警探
We're fine now, detective.
谢谢
Thank you.
听起来不像解决的样子
Doesn't sound resolved to me.
佩克问了关于机器的事
So Peck asks about your machine,
然后就有人要杀他
and now someone's trying to kill him.
想跟我说点什么吗  芬奇
Something you want to tell me, Finch?
正如所有的电脑系统一样
As with all computer systems,
最大的问题是人为错误
the big problem is human error.
严格来说  那台机器是违法的
Strictly speaking, the machine is not legal.
我一直都知道有特定的措施
I always knew that certain measures
来保护它  但是
would be taken to protect it, but...
但后来发现
but as I found out myself,
我没料到我所托付之人
the people I've entrusted it to are more...
竟如此残忍
ruthless than I anticipated.
-你好  -是佩克吗
- Hello? - Is this Peck?
是艾丽西娅・考文吗
Alicia Corwin?
考文
Corwin?
他想见的艾丽西亚是她
That's the Alicia he's trying to meet?
她之前为国安局工作
She worked for the National Security Council.
考文女士  你在听吗
Miss Corwin, are you there?
你在找我吗
You've been looking for me?
我们能面谈吗
Can we meet?
不能
No.
两个月前  我写的一份报告交至
Two months ago, a report I wrote was changed
你办公室时被篡改了
when it went through your office,
但你的办公室已被关闭一年多了
But your office has been shut down for more than a year.
拜托  我只想弄明白事情原委
Please, I just want to know what's going on.
我只想要回正常的生活
I just want my life back.
咝音
Sibilance.
好吧
Okay.
还有其他能告诉我的吗
Is there anything else you can tell me?
逃
Run.
我们得阻止他  里瑟先生
We need to stop him, Mr. Reese,
不能让他知道更多关于机器的事
from learning more about the machine,
还有咝音  不管那是什么
about Sibilance, whatever that is.
整个事就像传染病爆发
We need to treat this like an outbreak.
佩克被一个概念传染了
Peck is infected with an idea,
但传染就是传染
but infected all the same.
和他说话的人都可能死
Anybody he talks to can wind up dead,
佩克发现的每一点
And everything that Peck uncovers
都让我们救他的希望变得更加渺茫
makes it that much more impossible for us to save his life.
那就帮他找个藏身之地
So let's just get him to a safe house.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
他会想知道我们是谁
He'll want to know who we are,
而知道这一点会让他
And knowing that would put him closer
离发现机器更近一步
to finding out about the machine.
我们拯救佩克的同时
Whatever we do to save Peck,
必须不让他知晓我们的存在
it must be without him knowing that we exist.
里瑟先生  你有没有在听
Mr. Reese, are you even listening?
现在我们有更大的麻烦了
Well, now we have a bigger problem.
佩克发现了窃听器  把我们甩掉了
Peck found the bug, and he just gave us the slip.
佩克清空了银行存款
Peck's cashed out his bank accounts.
他的刷卡记录出现在全城各处的
His credit cards are popping up at cheap hotels
廉价酒店和酒类专卖店
and liquor stores all over the city.
他大概都施舍给了流浪汉
He's probably handing them out to the homeless.
国安局一定教会了他
The NSA certainly taught him
如何分散网络痕迹
how to scatter a digital footprint.
芬奇  佩克的手机上有发现吗
Finch, are you getting anything off Peck's phone?
不幸的是  他们也教会了他
Unfortunately, they taught him
如何拆散手机
how to brick a cell phone as well.
内存卡无法恢复
The flash memory is unrecoverable.
追杀他的人是什么情况
What can you tell us about the people hunting him?
一支精英小队
An elite squad,
大概是三人小组
probably a three-man team.
和我搏斗那人手枪里装备了步枪弹药
The guy I fought had a handgun chambered for rifle ammunition,
足以穿透防弹衣
So it shreds kevlar.
据我所知只有一支部队把它作为标准配备
Only one unit I know gave those as standard issue...
情报支援行动
Intelligence Support Activity,
一支隐秘性极高的特种部队
an obscure army unit that does black-ops so dark,
严格说来他们甚至不存在
technically, they don't exist.
看来我们最好抢先找到佩克
Guess we better find Peck first.
他们追杀步骤同我一样  从生活必需开始
They'll hunt him like I would, start with his needs...
一个能够睡觉  藏身  获取信息之处
Sleep, a place to hide, and a way to get information.
提供网络  只接收现金的酒店
Cash-only hotels with internet access.
出了点状况
There's been a complication.
目标仍在活动
the target's still in play.
这不是状况
That's not a complication.
这是失败
That's failure.
-他有后援  -是谁
- He has assistance. - Who?
不清楚  估计是我们的人
Unknown. One of ours, I think,
至少曾经是
or at least he used to be.
我们无法做到出其不意
We've lost the element of surprise
和伪造事故现场
and the ability to make it look like an accident.
行动命令是什么
What's the mandate?
放开手脚
Take the gloves off.
把这事结了
Get it done.
我有条线索  里瑟先生
I've got a hit, Mr. Reese,
地狱厨房的一间青年旅社
A youth hostel in Hell's Kitchen.
我不确定他是否现在还在
I can't be certain he's still there,
但佩克肯定用了那里的电脑
But peck Definitely used their computer.
他查不到关于咝音的任何信息
He wasn't able to dig up anything on Sibilance,
但幸运地找到了破解
but he had good luck finding a pinout
他办公室读卡机的方法
to hack the card reader at his office.
我想佩克先生打算闯进国安局
I believe Mr. Peck is planning to break into the NSA.
他进去了
He's in.
我也是
So am I.
如果你能阻止佩克获得更多
Then I'd very much appreciate it if you would stop Peck from
惹祸上身的信息我一定万分感激
getting any more information that'll get him killed.
现在是不是这样
Correct me if I'm wrong,
如果我去抢报告  他就会知道我的存在
but if I take those reports, he's gonna know I exist.
我知道这一情况很棘手
I recognize this is a challenging situation,
但你必须避免直接接触
but you have to avoid direct contact.
佩克
Peck!
你说对了  里瑟先生  是三人小组
You're right, Mr. Reese. It's a three-man team.
两人半了
2 1/2.
我刚刚非法闯入了那幢楼  知道不
Hey, I just broke in that building, okay?
你会逮捕我吧
You gonna arrest me?
你脑子坏了吗
What the hell's the matter with you?
别弄丢了  那是证据
Hey, don't lose those. That's evidence.
我供认的时候需要的
You're gonna want that when I confess.
放轻松  伙计  等我宣读完你的权利
Relax, pal. Soon as I read you your rights,
你就能畅所欲言了
you can tell us everything.
头低下
Get your head down.
芬奇
Finch?
情况不如你意了
You're not gonna like this.
一切就绪
Everything's in place.
点对点传输需要十天时间
Point-to-point transit will take ten days.
希望接下来十天内全世界都别出事
Hope nothing goes wrong in the rest of the world in ten days.
初始化
重启模式
权限管理
传输模式
关闭全系统
慢着
Wait.
我们有没有应急预案
Do we have a contingency?
应急预案
A contingency?
艾丽西亚有点  紧张
Alicia seemed... nervous.
万一政府决定
Now, what do we do
滥用这玩意儿  我们怎么办
if the government decides to abuse this thing?
他们是你联系的  奈森
They're your contacts, Nathan.
他们是普通人而已
They're just people.
这玩意儿所象征的权力
The power that this thing represents
你放心让谁拥有它呢
I mean, who would you trust it with?
除了你吗  没别人了
Besides you? No one.
所以我编码机器的方式是
Which is why the machine has been coded in such a way
无法破译的
that it cannot be abused.
甚至无法进入
It cannot even be accessed.
它自我更新  自我维护  自我修复
It upgrades itself, maintains itself, patches itself.
今晚过后  永远没人能改变机器了
After tonight, no one can alter it. Ever.
我曾是个软件工程师  哈罗德
I used to be a software engineer, Harold.
记得吗  在我变成你的对外掩护之前
Remember, back before I became your corporate beard?
任何系统都能被侵入  只是时间问题
Any system can be compromised, given enough time.
我们需要一个紧急开关  一个后门程序
We need an off switch, a back door,
而现在是我们最后的机会了
and this is our last chance to build one.
你是名出色的工程师  奈森
You are a talented engineer, Nathan,
所以你应该记得
so you should remember...
任何漏洞都可以被利用
any exploit is a total exploit.
千里之堤  溃于蚁穴
The tiniest crack becomes a flood.
如果我们在机器上建了后门程序
If we build a back door into this machine
而被别人发现了
and someone else finds out about it,
后果将  不堪设想
That would be...very bad.
我们应该信任机器  就如造它那般
We need to trust the machine, exactly as we built it,
然后放手
and then let it go.
初始化
重启模式
权限管理
传输模式
关闭全系统
全系统关闭
数据采集  离线
威胁识别  离线
核心分析  离线
三号车呼叫控制中心
Car three to central.
疑犯已被逮捕
Suspect in custody.
疑犯名叫佩克  亨利  L
Subject's name is Peck, Henry L.
我们有此人的通告
We've got a bolo on that guy.
把他押送给第八区的卡特警探
Take him to detective Carter at the eighth.
请听我说  他们毁了我的工作
Please just listen. They've taken my job,
毁了我的生活
ruined my life.
现在我知道原因了  这就是证据
Now I know why. This is the proof.
我给国安局写了六份报告
These are six reports I wrote for the NSA,
基于这些报告进行了六次秘密行动
and six covert actions based on those reports.
每次行动  报告中都增加了一个名字
In each case, a single name gets added to what I wrote,
而每一次  那个名字都被证实为
and each time, that name turns out to be
阻止重大恐怖袭击的关键
the key to stopping a major terrorist attack.
六次都是
Six for six.
如此精确的原因只可能是
The only way to be that accurate
超大规模的非法监控
is with illegal surveillance on a massive scale.
还有这个
Then there's this:
"咝音"是国安局的内网审核系统
"Sibilance" is an internal audit of the NSA intranet.
它平常都是例行公事
It's totally routine--
信道上无差错传输的最大传输速率
直到他们发现隐藏信号超过了香农极限
until they find signals hidden just beyond the Shannon limit.
那应该只有静电干扰  但是却出现了数据
It should just be static, but there was data.
有人秘密输出的数据规模超过了国安局
Someone is sneaking just as much data out as the NSA is taking in.
要完全扫描这些数据
To scan through all that,
需要十倍于我们规模的机构
you need an organization ten times our size.
这是任何人都无法
It's more than any human--
我的上帝  他们真造出来了
My God, they actually built it.
911事件后  政府想要
After 9/11, the government wanted
一个电脑系统  一台机器
a computer system--a machine--
来监视一切人一切事
that could watch everyone and everything,
在恐怖分子袭击之前就抓住他们
catch terrorists before they strike.
他们试过先驱计划  TIA计划  星风计划
They tried with trailblazer, TIA, stellar wind.
皆为美国政府主导基于反恐的信息收集和整理计划
但  但都失败了
They--they all failed.
但如果我没猜错
But if I'm right,
后来确实有人把这玩意儿造出来了
then someone really built the damn thing,
而我们正在被监视着
and it's watching us right now.
好吧  你要来点汽水不
Okay, you want a soda or something?
你审问了我的嫌犯
You just questioned my suspect?
审问你的嫌犯吗
Questioned your suspect?
那家伙自说自话  没玩没了
Guy's in there talking a blue streak all by himself.
简直有被害妄想狂
Should be wearing a tin foil hat.
昨天因藏毒被捕
Gets arrested yesterday for drugs,
今天又朝警察扔杯子
Tonight he throws a bottle at a cop--
那家伙疯了
This guy's out of his mind.
我们得赶快离开这里  亨利
We need to get you out of here, Henry.
你是谁
Who are you?
我想我们可以指望
I suppose we can count our blessings
弗斯科警探并非好奇宝宝
Detective Fusco isn't the inquisitive type.
但佩克的处境更危险了
But Peck's in more danger than ever.
说真的  你到底是谁
Seriously, who the hell are you?
亨利只是问了问题
All Henry peck did was ask questions.
他应该拥有正常的生活
He deserves a normal life,
如果我们想实现这一点
and if we have any hope of giving it to him,
就必须销毁所有证据
we have to destroy all that evidence
并阻止他得到更多证据
and stop him from getting any more.
喂  我叫亨利・佩克
Yes, my name is Henry Peck.
-我是一个分析师  -你电话打给谁了
- I'm an analyst-- - who did you just call?
特别检察官办公室
The office of special counsel.
是保护检举人的机构
It's the agency that protects whistleblowers.
真希望你没让他打那个电话  里瑟先生
I really wish you hadn't let him do that, Mr. Reese.
知道这台机器的人之一
The people who know about the machine,
就在特别检察官办公室工作
one of them works for the office of special counsel.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我们的政府在监视我们
Our own government is spying on us
还想杀了我掩盖事实
and they want to kill me to cover it up.
我必须告诉别人
I have to tell someone!
你打电话的人不是你所想的
The people you called aren't who you think they are.
任何人都不能告诉  任何人都不可靠
There's no one to tell. No one is safe.
他刚刚打电话给我们了
He just called us.
我把他们最近的已知坐标发给你
I'm sending their last known coordinates.
足够了
That's all I need.
趴下
Get down.
你知道为什么下令杀他吗
Do you know why you were ordered to kill him?
永不提问
Never asked.
好了  佩克  我们赶快离开
Okay, Peck, let's get you out of--
事情还没完  芬奇
This isn't over, Finch.
那家伙连超速罚单都要写78页的报告申诉
The man wrote 78 pages to fight a speeding ticket.
我知道  他不会放弃的
I know. He's not gonna give up.
那些知道机器存在的人也不会放弃
And neither are the people who know about the machine.
那我们到底要怎么办
So what the hell are we gonna do?
一位好朋友曾经让我看到
A good friend once showed me that,
即使是棘手的问题
even with an intractable problem,
也能找到法子做正确的事
one can still find a way to do the right thing.
已识别主体
姓名  奈森・英格拉姆
社保号码  XXX-XX-1860
权限  已限制
初始化
重启模式
权限管理
传输模式
关闭全系统
已识别主体
姓名  奈森・英格拉姆
社保号码  XXX-XX-1860
权限
已限制
许可
系统更新
进入核心代码
创建新功能
名称  应急预案
你的行动失败了
Your predecessors failed,
佩克现在已经开始接触媒体
and now peck's reaching out to the press.
他明天要见一名记者
He's meeting a reporter tomorrow.
我要你除掉他们两个
I want you to silence them both.
我们会的
We'll be there.
你不是记者
You're not the reporter.
不不  我不是  她现在很安全
No. No, I'm not. She's quite safe.
现在  我的伙伴正在处理
Right now, my associate is dealing
要暗杀你们两人的刺客
with the assassins who were sent to kill you both.
你的问题  答案是  是
The answer to your question is yes.
它存在
It exists.
而且此刻正在监视着我们
And it's watching us right now.
我告诉你此事
I'm telling you this
是因为我在你身上看到了自己的影子
because you remind me a little of myself.
而且我知道  如果我是你
And I know that, if I were you,
我会穷追不舍直至找出真相
I would keep asking until I knew the truth.
现在你找出来了
So now you do.
不要再问了
Now stop asking the question.
它在哪儿
Where is it?
它怎么工作  那些服务器单独
How does it work? I mean, the servers alone--
我知道你的感受
I know how you feel.
你想知道
Your need to understand.
但相信我  佩克先生
But believe me, Mr. Peck,
这是你不该去解的谜团
This is a mystery you do not want to solve.
知道答案
Knowing the answer
使我失去了爱愈生命的东西
has cost me something I value more than my own life.
新护照  机票
Clean passport, plane tickets,
用你的新名字办的银行卡  里边有不少钱
a bank card to a well-funded account in your new name.
拜托了  佩克先生  为了你自己好
Please, Mr. Peck, for your own sake--
坦白说  也为了我
and quite frankly, for mine--
去过你自己的生活吧
Go and live your life.
找些属于你的秘密
Find some secrets of your own.
如果你真的需要一个谜团
And if you really need a mystery,
去研究人心吧
I recommend the human heart.
你是怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
因为它是我造的
Because I built it.
-卡特  -什么事
- Carter. - Yeah?
那个玩"大变活人"的家伙佩克
That guy Peck who pulled the disappearing act,
我们从一辆烧毁的出租车里找到了
we just pulled his prints off a burnt-out cab
他的指纹  还有一具无名尸
with a John Doe next to it.
那佩克人呢  知道他在哪儿吗
What about Peck? Any idea where he is now?
他已经没影儿了
He's in the wind.
一叠文件在车里被烧掉了
A bunch of paper burned up in that cab.
我们只拿到这个
All we could make out was this.
咝音
那个HR的事儿定了
Hey, this H.R. deals a lock.
我们有三天时间准备
We get three days to prepare.
到底做不做
Now we gonna do this or not?
我们会准备好的
We'll be ready.
这边一忙完我就给电话你
I'll call you as soon as I'm done here.
是啊  对呢
Yeah, right.
好像你能停止偷窥眼镜先生似的
Like you'll ever be done spying on Mr. Glasses.
下次见你时  我可能已经有他家的住址了
Next time I see you, I just might have his address.
约翰  你的茶好了
John, your order's ready.
煎绿茶
克雷默纸业公司
编号JGS-0031
你每天都在这里吗
And you're here every day?
《本区》
你好啊  芬奇
Hello, Finch.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to bother you.
我是斯蒂尔斯警探
Detective Stills.
有人举报说这里有情况
Someone reported a disturbance at this address.
真的吗  我一个人住这里
Really? I'm the only one here.
很可能某位老人杯弓蛇影
Probably just an old lady who saw a shadow
或某个孩子的恶作剧
or a kid playing a joke.
我们还是得检查一下
We just have to check everything out.
需要我帮您拿进去吗
Do you want help with these?
好啊  谢谢
Sure. Thanks.
这大概有五十份呢
There must be about 50 copies here.
您是收藏吗
You a collector?
算是吧
Kind of.
他们会送我一些刊登有我作品的杂志
They send me extras when it's one of mine.
您是封面画家
You draw the covers.
是啊  有点太传统  我知道
Yeah. A bit old-fashioned, I know.
一切都数字化了  传统印刷正被淘汰
Everything's going digital. Print is dying.
但是  每次我觉得我肯定没活儿干时
But, every time I think I'll never work again,
别的杂志或报社就会来电话  所以
another magazine or newspaper calls, so...
我想我有个守护天使
Guess I have a guardian angel.
他是谁
Who's this?
那是哈罗德  我的未婚夫
That's Harold, my fiance.
看上去人很好
Looks like a nice guy.
是啊
Yeah.
他人非常好
He's a very nice guy.
我从没想到我能遇到一个懂我的人
I never really thought that I'd meet anyone who got me.
把所有的时间都用来画画
You know, spending all your time alone, drawing,
可不容易找到真爱
isn't exactly the best way to find someone.
但哈罗德找到了我
But Harold found me.
那天我在公园里画画
I was painting in the park one day,
然后  这个男人出现了
And...there was this man,
一月天里  吃着冰淇淋
Eating an ice cream cone in January.
冲我微笑
And he smiled at me.
问我想不想要一个
He asked me if I wanted one.
他跟你住在一起吗
Does he live here with you?
不  没有
No, he doesn't.
以前是
He used to.
两年前我失去了他
I lost him two years ago.
发生了一场意外
There was an accident.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
地方选得不错
Good location.
视线清楚
Clear line of sight,
又有足够的遮挡物和距离
but enough obstructions and distance
防止她看到你
to avoid being seen.
我编写了一个程序
I built an app that alerts me
如果我和她距离一百米之内就会提醒我
if I ever get within 100 meters of her.
我从未后悔造了那台机器
I've never regretted building the machine.
但我以前没有充分意识到我要为此付出的代价
But I didn't fully realize the personal cost.
我很擅长电脑
I'm good with computers.
但人  除了格蕾斯之外
People--well, people other than Grace--
对我来说一直是个谜
have always been a mystery to me.
我并没意识到
I failed to recognize the lengths
他们为保护和控制机器不惜耗尽漫长的时光
to which they would go to protect the machine, to control it.
当我意识到时候  对我来说  为时已晚
By the time I realized it, it was too late...for me.
但对她还不晚
But not for her.
你看  里瑟先生
You see, Mr. Reese,
如果知道机器的存在是个病毒
If knowing about the machine is like a virus,
那我就是第一感染源
that makes me patient zero.
只是在我身边都会危及她的安全
Simply being near me was putting her life in danger.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我已经很幸运了
I was lucky.
我拥有四年的
I had four years of...
幸福时光
happiness.
有些人只有四天
Some people only get four days.
2012年5月
2012年5月10日
2012年5月9日
拜托了  佩克先生  为了你自己好
Please, Mr. Peck, for your own sake--
坦白说  也为了我
And quite frankly, for mine--
去过你自己的生活吧
Go live your life.
找些属于你的秘密
Find some secrets of your own.
如果你真的需要一个谜团
And if you really need a mystery,
去研究人心吧
I recommend the human heart.
你是怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
因为它是我造的
Because I built it.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第22集
Person of Interest S01E22 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-